Gheorghe Craciun

iOS Developer







linkedin.com/gheorghecraciun



07927769866



github.com/gheorghecr



Portfolio

Profile

An undergraduate student currently in the third year, studying BSc (Hons) in Computer Science at Coventry University.

A pro-active and quick learner student who has excellent problem-solving skills, highly interested in Software development, with strong attention to details and passionate for learning new things to keep up to date with current technologies.

Able to collaborate with others but also able to work independently in order to achieve objectives on time and with excellence, demonstrated experience in developing software and web applications. Known as a self-starter who has been studying programming for the past six years.

Technical Proficiencies

- Most Experienced with Swift, Python, Java
- Some Experience with C#, SwiftUI, Firebase
- Beginner with HTML5, CSS, PHP, Java Script.
- Professional experience using Agile methodology
- Familiarity of XCode, Android Studio, Visual Studio and IntelliJ IDEA
- Experience in relations databases such as SQL and NoSQL
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Knowledge of Unit Testing

Soft Skills

- Ability to work under pressure
- Adaptability
- Analytical
- Creativity
- Decision making
- Optimist
- Time management

Practical Skills

Languages:

Portuguese: Native

Romanian: Native

English: Fluent

Spanish: Intermediate

• Russian: Beginner

Full UK Driving License

Education

Coventry University

BSc (Hons) Computer Science – 2nd Year result: 2:1 (68%).

(September 2017 – Present)

Polytechnic Institute of Setubal

(October 2016 – July 2017)

Web Programming, Mobile Devices and Applications: Final Project – 80%.

Dr José Afonso High School

(September 2013 – June 2016)

Computer Systems Programming and Management Technician: Final Mark – 80%.

Interests



Programming



Reading



Travelling



Portuguese Society at Coventry University



Futsal



Swimming

Employment History

Software Developer / Data Analyst EriccTS Ltd – Birmingham, United Kingdom (July 2019 – July 2020)

- Intern for one year.
- iOS application development for a big multi-national retailer.
- Java/JavaFX touchscreen desktop application development for a big multi-national retailer.
- Data Analyst in order to help stores to improve energy consumption that saved money for the store.

Technician Pahldata – Lisbon, Portugal (May – July 2015 / January – March 2016)

- Intern in total for 6 months.
- Repair and configure communications equipment using C language.
- Deliver and install communication equipment.
- Teaching sessions about programming routers on C language with other employees.

Restaurant Supervisor Days Hotel – Coventry, United Kingdom (August 2017 – July 2018)

- Train new and current employees on how to use the till software ICRTOUCH made me a reliable.
- Handling customer inquiries and complaints about service or food quality required to take actions which made me be a good problem solver.
- Take food/drinks orders and bring to the tables this requires good communication skills to make sure
 everything is correct.
- Replenishing and restocking the bar, always ensuring a high level of stock management efficiency and organizing rotas made me gain reasonability.

Project Experience

EriccTS APP - iOS App

- Sole Developer
- Designed, developed and tested the EriccTS application for iOS/macOS devices using Swift 5
- Understanding of UIKit, Cocoa Touch, Cocoa Pods, Core Animation, Networking, Core Data, Storyboards
- Working on agile scrum methodology and involving in stand-up meeting to monitor the progress
- Experienced with MVC design pattern and Unit Tests with XCTest.
- Worked with RESTful Web Services using URLSession
- Applied TCP Connections between the server and the app
- In-app messaging system built from scratch
- Successfully launched the application to the APP Store, only available internally
- Used GIT for version controller

EriccTS Java/JavaFX - Desktop App

- Team Member
- Designed, developed and tested a touchscreen application
- Working on agile scrum methodology and involving in stand-up meetings to monitor the progress
- Applied TCP Connections
- Applied MVC design pattern
- Used GIT for version controller

References: available on request.